Guide to the John Hay Whitney and Betsey Cushing Whitney Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Photographs, 1854-2000; Series IV
  - Topical
    - Properties
      - Greentree, Manhasset, New York
        - Garden, 1990-1991, 1995 (Box 347, Folder 6-8)
          Includes images of the 1995 New York Flower Show where the Greentree garden won awards for exceptional achievement and best in show for landscape and garden design.
      - Greenwood, Thomasville, Georgia
        - Circa 1930-1940 (Box 348, Folder 1)
          Includes images of white and African-American staff, as well as the grounds and farm.
          - Oversize (Box 406, Folder 3)
        - Circa 1990 (Box 348, Folder 2-3)
          Includes images of the fire that partially destroyed Greenwood.
        - 1992 (Box 348, Folder 4-5)
        - 1993-1994 (Box 349, Folder 1-8)
          Contains images of the renovation following the fire.
      - Llangollen Estate, Upperville, Virginia, construction, Circa 1930-1940 (Box 349, Folder 9)
      - Plandome Manor, construction and exterior, Circa 1930-1940 (Box 349, Folder 10)
      - Saratoga Springs, New York, Circa 1950-1960, circa 1990-2000 (Box 350–351)
        - Oversize (Box 407, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Europe, Circa 1930-1940 (Box 352, Folder 1)
    - Individuals and places (oversize prints), Undated (Box 407, Folder 2)
    - South Asian expedition (oversize), Circa 1880-1890 (Box 407, Folder 3)
  - Unidentified, Undated (Box 352, Folder 2)
    - Oversize (Box 407, Folder 4)
- Scrapbooks, 1860-1995; Series V
  The scrapbooks contain correspondence, photographs in various formats, clippings, and ephemera documenting all aspects of Whitney family life, primarily for the years 1880 to 1970. Although most of the correspondence in the series is routine and social in nature, there are substantive letters scattered throughout.
  The series is arranged in three sections: Family, Individuals, and Topical. Materials in each section are arranged chronologically.
  - Family
    - Whitney Family, Circa 1898-1930 (Box 353, Folder 1)
    - JHW & BCW (John Hay Whitney and Betsey Cushing Whitney), Circa 1945 (Box 354, Folder 1-2)
    - Captiva: Winter 1953 (Box 355, Folder 1)
    - Whitney Family, 1956-1958 (Box 355, Folder 2)
    - London, ambassador years
      - Volumes 1-3, 1957-1959 (Box 356, Folder 1-3)
      - Volumes 4-6, 1959-1960 (Box 357, Folder 1-3)
      - Volumes 7-8, 1960-1961 (Box 410, Folder 1-2)
    - Whitney Family, 1961-1965 (Box 358, Folder 1-7)
    - Whitney Family, 1961-1966 (Box 359, Folder 1)
    - Whitney Family, 1962-1963 (Box 359, Folder 2-6)
    - Whitney Family, 1963-1968 (Box 360, Folder 1-2)
      - Loose materials (Box 361, Folder 1-12)
    - Whitney Family, Circa 1965-1995 (Box 362, Folder 1-6)
    - Whitney Family, Circa 1970-1980 (Box 363, Folder 1)
  - Individuals
    - Hay, John M., "John Hay: Letters of Congratulation and Farewell", 1898 (Box 364, Folder 1)
      Contains letters of congratulation for John M. Hay's appointment as secretary of state under William McKinley in 1898.
    - Whitney, Betsey Cushing
      - Betsey Cushing Whitney on Cushing family, Circa 1898-1940 (Box 365, Folder 1-7)
        Photographs of Cushing family members compiled by Betsey Cushing Whitney. Contains tintypes, cartes-de-visite, cabinet cards, postcards and photographic prints.
      - London Letters
        Includes letters from Fred Astaire, Vivien Leigh, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Truman Capote, Queen Elizabeth and Jacqueline Kennedy.
        - Volumes 1-2, 1957-1961 (Box 366, Folder 1-2)
        - Volumes 3-4, 1957-1983 (Box 367, Folder 1-2)
      - Betsey Cushing Whitney Get Well, 1991 (Box 368, Folder 1-2)
        - Loose materials (Box 369, Folder 1-3)
    - Whitney, Helen Hay
      - Helen Hay Whitney: a Collection of Poems and Verse, Circa 1890-1910 (Box 370, Folder 1-3)
        Consists of writing by others.
      - Helen Hay Whitney, Circa 1890-1920 (Box 370, Folder 4-9)
      - Helen Hay, Circa 1890-1930 (Box 371, Folder 1-3)
      - Helen Hay, 1891-1897 (Box 372)
        Documents Helen Hay's travels to Europe and contains tintypes of family and friends.
      - Helen Hay Whitney, 1898-1902 (Box 373, Folder 1-3)
    - Whitney, John Hay
      - General
        - John Hay Whitney, Circa 1920-1980 (Box 408, Folder 2)
        - John Hay Whitney, 1921-1926 (Box 374, Folder 1-2)
        - America's No. 1 Angel, 1940 (Box 374, Folder 3)
        - JHW (John Hay Whitney), Circa 1960 (Box 375)
        - Jock, 1981-1982 (Box 376, Folder 1)
      - Topical
        - Ambassadorial years
          - John Hay Whitney Appointed Ambassador to St. James's, 1956-1957 (Box 377, Folder 1)
          - Clubland, Circa 1957 (Box 377, Folder 2)
        - Crew, 1922-1926 (Box 378, Folder 1)
        - Film industry
          - Film and Political Correspondence, 1935-1961 (Box 410, Folder 3)
            Includes correspondence from Ingmar Bergman, Margaret Mitchell, John Foster Dulles, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Henry Cabot Lodge, and Richard Nixon.
          - Gone with the Wind Premiere, 1939 (Box 379, Folder 1)
        - First Flight Air Mail Covers, 1940-1942 (Box 380, Folder 1-2)
        - J. H. Whitney & Company, 1937-1959 (Box 380, Folder 3)
        - John Hay Whitney Collection at the National Gallery of Art, Washington, D.C., 1983 (Box 412, Folder 1)
          - Loose materials (Box 381, Folder 1-5)
        - New York Herald Tribune
          - New York Herald Tribune Historical, 1871-1971 (Box 408, Folder 1)
          - New York Herald Tribune European Edition, 75th Anniversary, 1962 (Box 408, Folder 3)
          - New York Herald Tribune, White House cancellation of, 1962 (Box 412, Folder 2)
          - John F. Kennedy Assassination, 1963 (Box 409, Folder 1)
            Collected front pages of the New York Herald Tribune during the month of November 1963.
          - New York Herald Tribune, 1965-1966 (Box 409, Folder 2)
          - The Death of the Herald Tribune, 1965-1978 (Box 382, Folder 1-4)
          - New York Herald Tribune, Doomsday
            - Volume 1, 1966 (Box 409, Folder 3)
            - Volume 2, 1966 (Box 411, Folder 1)
            - Volume 3, 1966 (Box 411, Folder 2)
              This scrapbook includes letters and telegrams to John Hay Whitney regarding the New York Herald Tribune 's decision to cease publication in New York.
            - Volume 4, 1966 (Box 411, Folder 3)
          - New York Herald Tribune closing, 1966-1967 (Box 412, Folder 3)
          - Transition, 1978 (Box 383, Folder 1-2)
            Chronicles the International Herald Tribune's transition from manual to electronic production in 1978 through photographs and press releases.
        - Political
          - Political Correspondence, 1954-1961 (Box 410, Folder 4)
            Includes correspondence from Harold MacMillan and William Paley.
          - Political Correspondence, 1957-1965 (Box 410, Folder 5)
            Includes correspondence from Lyndon Johnson, Robert F. Kennedy, Richard Nixon, Dwight D. Eisenhower, and Prince Philip.
          - Whitney Family Political Correspondence, 1965-1979 (Box 384, Folder 1)
            Includes correspondence from Dwight D. Eisenhower, Nelson Rockefeller, Jacob Javitz, John Lindsay, and Richard Nixon.
    - Whitney, Payne, "In Memoriam: Payne Whitney", 1927 (Box 385)
      Clippings on Whitney's estate, philanthropy, and accomplishments. Includes obituaries.
  - Topical
    - Li'l Abner, Circa 1934-1977 (Box 386, Folder 1-2)
    - Newport, Rhode Island, Circa 1906 (Box 387, Folder 1-3)
    - Poetry, Undated (Box 388, Folder 1-2)
    - Properties
      - Greenwood, Thomasville, Georgia, Circa 1860-1920 (Box 389, Folder 1)
        Contains exterior photographs of the Greenwood buildings and grounds, photographs of the Greenwood Negro School and its students, as well as photographs of the property and its original owner during the antebellum period.
      - Fishers Island, 1948-1950 (Box 389, Folder 2)
        Documents the construction of the Whitney's summer house on Fishers Island.
    - Thoroughbreds at Greentree, Circa 1930-1940 (Box 390, Folder 1)
    - Wilde, Oscar, Circa 1882 (Box 390, Folder 2)
      Contains copies of Wilde's poems and copies of two letters Wilde and Joaquin Miller exchanged in February 1882.
- Additional Material, 1840-2010; Accession 2011-M-063
  This accession is arranged in three sections: Family Papers; Photographs; and Scrapbooks/Photograph albums.
  The accession consists of correspondence, diaries, topical files, newspaper clippings, photographs, and scrapbooks documenting several members of the Whitney and Cushing families. The papers were maintained by the Whitney family separately from the papers in Series I-V and are of a more personal nature. The material in the accession primarily relates to Betsey Cushing Whitney, John Hay Whitney, Harvey Cushing, and Kate Crowell Cushing. While some of the papers supplement Series I-V, the majority of the papers in the accession substantively enhance the documentation on the personal lives of Betsey Cushing Whitney, both before and during her marriage to John Hay Whitney, and her parents, Harvey Cushing and Kate Crowell Cushing.
  The most substantive material in the accession is Betsey Cushing Whitney's correspondence, filed throughout the Family Papers section. It includes incoming and outgoing letters, most of which date from the 1920s to the 1950s. Primarily to and from family and friends, the letters discuss activities, travels, relationships, and news. They provide insight into her close relationships with her parents and sisters, Mary Cushing Fosburgh and Barbara Cushing Paley; her marriage to James Roosevelt; her experiences in the White House during the Roosevelt administration; and her life with John Hay Whitney. Correspondence between Betsey Cushing Whitney and John Hay Whitney, including letters written during their courtship and while John Hay Whitney was in the service, document their early relationship and John Hay Whitney's capture by and escape from the Germans. Letters written to family from London in 1957 through 1961 provide rich details of the family's experiences while John Hay Whitney served as Ambassador to the Court of St. James's.
  The accession also includes material on the Cushing side of Betsey Cushing Whitney's family, of which there is little in Series I-V. In addition to the correspondence from Betsey Cushing Whitney to her parents and sisters, the papers include a limited number of incoming letters from family and friends to Harvey and Kate Crowell Cushing; diaries of Mary Benedict Crowell (Betsey Cushing Whitney's grandmother), Kate Crowell Cushing, and Mary Cushing Fosburgh; and biographical material on Harvey Cushing. The diaries of Kate Crowell Cushing are the most extensive. Although the entries are generally short and routine, more detailed entries describe her honeymoon and early years of marriage to Harvey Cushing.
  The Photographs are arranged in two groups: Families/Individuals and Topical and alphabetically therein. The Scrapbooks/Photograph albums are arranged alphabetically by name or topic. Together they document many aspects of Whitney and Cushing family life, primarily between the years of 1890 and 1960. The photographs in the accession document members of the Cushing family not included in Series IV and V and the scrapbooks/photograph albums relate only to the Cushings.
  - Family papers
    The materials are arranged by family.
    - John Hay Whitney and Betsey Cushing Whitney family
      - Clippings, 1929-2002, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
      - Whitney, Betsey Cushing
        - Biographical
          - Clothes, swatches, Circa 1980-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
          - Death of Betsey Cushing Whitney
            - Correspondence
              - A-F, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 2-15)
              - G-K, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 1-10)
              - L-R, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1-17)
              - S-Y, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 1-10)
              - Unidentified, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 11)
            - Memorial luncheon at Greentree, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 12)
            - Memorial service, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 13)
          - Embassy wives activities, Circa 1960 (Box 5, Folder 13a)
          - White House years
            See also: Writings, White House reflections, Box 6, folder 3 and Scrapbook, White House Years, box 47, folder 5.
            - Memorabilia, 1932-1945 (Box 5, Folder 14)
              Includes guest passes for the Democratic Convention and cards from the Roosevelts.
            - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, inauguration, 1941-1945 (Box 5, Folder 15)
            - Royal visit, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 16)
              Includes correspondence, photographs, and ephemera.
          - Writings
            - Diary, European trip, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 17)
            - Paley, Barbara, account of, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
            - Sandringham estate, visit with Queen, Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
            - White House reflections, Circa 1936-1941 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - Correspondence
          - Incoming
            - A, 1940, 1965-1966, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 4)
            - B, 1940-1964 (Box 6, Folder 5)
            - Barnes, Janet and Tracy, 1958-1970, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
            - Beaton, Cecil, Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
            - Bowes-Lyon, John, 1986, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 8)
            - Bullitt, William, Jr., 1957 (Box 6, Folder 9)
            - C, 1936-1964 (Box 6, Folder 10)
            - Cecil, David (Lord) and (Lady) Rachel, 1957-1968, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
            - Churchill, Clementine, 1957, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
            - Clark, Edmond (cousin), 1950-1953 (Box 6, Folder 13)
              Includes material for book about Kate Crowell Cushing.
            - Claunch, C. K., 1940 (Box 6, Folder 14)
            - Cole, Corinne Alsop, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 15)
            - Coward, Noel, 1949, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 16)
            - Crown Prince and Princess of Norway, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 17)
            - Cushing, Harvey, 1933-1939 (Box 6, Folder 18)
            - Cushing, Harvey, condolences on death of
              - 1939 October 7-9 (Box 6, Folder 19)
              - 1939 October 10-11 (Box 6, Folder 20)
              - 1939 October 12-November 3 (Box 6, Folder 21)
              - Telegrams, 1939 October 7-10 (Box 6, Folder 22)
              - Undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
            - "Cushing at the Countway" (article), 1979 (Box 7, Folder 1)
            - Cushing, Harvey, letters about, 1925, 1959-1998 (Box 7, Folder 2)
            - Cushing, Harvey, plaque at Cleveland Health Sciences Library, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 3)
            - Cushing, Harvey, radio dramatization, 1987, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
            - Cushing, Harvey, stamp, White House unveiling, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 5)
            - Cushing, Henry K., 1935-1972, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
            - Cushing, Kate Crowell
              - 1931-1935 (Box 7, Folder 7)
              - 1936-1941 (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
              - 1942-1949 (Box 7, Folder 10)
              - Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
            - Cushing, Kate Crowell, condolences on illness and death of
              - 1949 April-May 8 (Box 8, Folder 1)
              - 1949 May 9-10 (Box 8, Folder 2)
              - 1949 May 11-June 17 (Box 8, Folder 3)
              - Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
            - Cushing, Mary, 1936-1940, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
            - D, 1936, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 6)
            - Di Bonaventura family, Undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
            - Di Bonaventura, Andrea Isabelle, 1960-1995 (Box 8, Folder 8)
            - Di Bonaventura, Betsey Maria, Undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
            - Di Bonaventura, Chris, 1968-1990, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
            - Di Bonaventura, Rose, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 11)
            - Douglas-Home, Elizabeth, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 12)
            - Duchin, Peter, Undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
            - Early, Stephen, 1938-1940, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
            - Eisenhower, Dwight D. and Mamie, Circa 1955-1974 (Box 8, Folder 15)
            - Elizabeth II, Queen of Great Britain, 1957-1997 (Box 8, Folder 16)
            - Embassy departure, 1960-1961 (Box 9, Folder 1)
            - Employees, 1943, 1958-1959 (Box 9, Folder 2)
            - Etting, Gloria Braggiotti, 1939-1963, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
            - F, 1960-1967 (Box 9, Folder 4)
            - Farley, James, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 5)
            - Fonteyn, Margot, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 6)
            - Fosburgh family, Undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
            - Fosburgh, Mary Cushing, 1940-1969, undated (Box 9, Folder 8-14)
            - Fosburgh, Mary, headstone, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 15)
            - G, 1941, 1959, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
            - Gelhorn, Martha, 1959-1964, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
            - Givenchy, Hubert, 1969, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 18)
            - Greenwald, Virginia, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 19)
            - Guion, Connie, 1950-1969 (Box 10, Folder 1)
            - H, 1945, 1957, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
            - Harriman, Pamela Churchill, 1957-1960, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
            - Harrison, Rex, Undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
            - Harrold, Anne Maud, 1938-1959, 1978, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
            - Harvey Cushing Society; American Association of Neurological Surgeons, 1944, 1969, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 6)
            - Herlihy, Maud O'Shea, 1958-1960, 1986-1990, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
            - Hopkins, Harry, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 8)
            - Hospital stay, Betsey Cushing Whitney, 1956-1957 (Box 10, Folder 9)
            - Humphrey, George Magoffin and Pamela, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 10)
            - Ickes, Harold and Jane, 1938-1940 (Box 10, Folder 11)
            - J, 1939-1959, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
            - Jackson, William, 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 13)
            - Kahn, Eli Jacques, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 14)
            - Kelly, Felix, Undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
            - Kelly, John Sims (Shipwreck), 1954-1970, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
            - Kennedy, Jacqueline, 1964-1965, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
            - Kennedy, Rose, 1968, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
            - Kim, Yu Taik, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 19)
            - Knauer, William, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 20)
            - Kurnitz, Henry, 1960, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
            - L, 1963-1965 (Box 10, Folder 22)
            - Lambton, Belinda (Bindy), 1990, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
            - Lineaweaver, Meems (Mimi), 1957-1958, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 24)
            - M, 1936-1941, 1959-1962 (Box 10, Folder 25)
            - Macmillan, Harold, 1968-1971 (Box 10, Folder 26)
            - Malik, Madame, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 27)
            - Margaret, Princess, Countess of Snowden and Anthony Armstrong Jones, 1965, 1971, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
            - McCrary, Jinx and Tex, 1958, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
            - McDonald, Stewart, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 3)
            - McIntire, Ross, 1938, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 4)
            - McMein, Neysa and John C. Baragwanath, 1959, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
            - Montagu, Judith Venetia and Milton Gendel, 1950-1995 (Box 11, Folder 6-7)
            - New York Herald Tribune, 1957-1968, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
              Includes correspondence from Joseph Wright Alsop.
            - Nicolson, Harold, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 2)
            - Niven, David, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 3)
            - North Shore University Hospital, Manhasset, New York, 1993-1995 (Box 12, Folder 4)
            - O, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 5)
            - Offie, C., 1942, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 6)
            - Ormsby-Gore, David, 5th Baron Harlech and Lady Harlech, 1964-1968, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
            - P, 1932-1961, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
            - Paley family, 1972, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
            - Paley, Barbara (Babe) Cushing, 1931-1969, undated (Box 12, Folder 10-17)
            - Parish, Sister, 1960, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
            - Payson family, 1958, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
            - Payson, Danny, 1944-1945 (Box 13, Folder 2)
            - Payson, Joan, 1921-1960, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
            - R, 1942-1989 (Box 13, Folder 4)
            - Rewald, John, 1968, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
            - Roosevelt family, 1929-1946, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
            - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1929-1959, undated (Box 13, Folder 7-11)
            - Roosevelt, Eleanor and Franklin Delano, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 12)
            - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano
              - General, 1930-1944 (Box 13, Folder 13-14)
              - Marion Dickerman, correspondence on film footage, 1964-1970 (Box 13, Folder 15)
              - Memorial service, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 16)
            - Roosevelt, James, 1929-1941 (Box 13, Folder 17)
            - Roosevelt, Sara Delano, 1929-1941, undated (Box 13, Folder 18-21)
            - Rowe, James, Jr., 1939-1942 (Box 14, Folder 1)
            - Royal family (Windsor), 1953-1998, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
            - S, 1939-1997, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
            - Saratoga Performing Arts Center, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 4)
            - Selznick, Irene Mayer, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 5)
            - Sherwood, Robert and Mado, 1941, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 6)
            - Sholis, Victor, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 7)
            - Simonné, Buia, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 8)
            - Sitwell, Edith and Osbert, 1940-1967 (Box 14, Folder 9-11)
            - Spivack, Sydney S., 1943-1951, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 12)
            - Spruks, E. Charles, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 13)
            - Straight family, 1965, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 14)
            - Sutherland, Graham, 1964-1968 (Box 14, Folder 15)
            - Symington family, 1957-1960, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
            - Thomson, Elizabeth, 1980-1987 (Box 14, Folder 17)
            - Tree, Jeremy, 1970, undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
            - Tully, Grace, 1938-1942 (Box 14, Folder 19)
            - W, 1941-1964 (Box 14, Folder 20)
            - Wald, Richard C., 1968-1971 (Box 14, Folder 21)
            - Watson, Edwin, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 22)
            - Wedding to John Hay Whitney, congratulations, 1942 March 1 (Box 14, Folder 23)
            - Whitney family, 1950, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
            - Whitney, Helen Hay, condolences on death of, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 2)
            - Whitney, John Hay
              - General
                - 1940-1954 (Box 15, Folder 3-8)
                - 1957-1965, undated (Box 16, Folder 1-3)
              - Capture and escape, 1944 (Box 16, Folder 4-6)
            - Whitney, Kate Roosevelt, 1942-1950, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
            - Wisner, Frank A., 1984, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
            - Yale University Medical Library
              - Cushing exhibit, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 9)
              - Expansion and development, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 10)
            - Zuckerman, Lord Solly, 1964-1971 (Box 16, Folder 11)
            - Unidentified, 1921-1966, undated (Box 17, Folder 1-9)
          - Outgoing (to family members)
            Consists of letters to family (in general) and pages from a diary or journal written while living in London during John Hay Whitney's tenure as ambassador.
            - 1957-1958 (Box 18, Folder 1)
            - 1959 (Box 18, Folder 2)
            - 1960 (Box 18, Folder 3)
            - 1961 (Box 18, Folder 4)
            - Circa 1960 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Whitney, John Hay
        - Biographical
          - General, 1935-1964 (Box 19, Folder 1)
          - Adoption of Kate and Sara Roosevelt, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 2)
          - Baptismal certificate, 1905 (Box 19, Folder 3)
          - Memorial, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 4)
          - Military service records